neatorama.com 2009-12-03

# Privacy Policy – Neatorama

At Neatorama.com, we appreciate your readership and respect your privacy. This privacy policy governs the way we collect and use your personal information. This policy may be revised or updated at any time, so please check back often to find the latest version.

**Collection and Use of Personal Information**

Neatorama.com has four main parts: blog, forum, Upcoming Queue, and online shop. You may register a username in order to comment on the blog, though you are not required to do so (i.e. you can comment without registering a username). You are required to register a username in order to post in the forum, and submit a post or comment in the Upcoming Queue. For username registration, a valid email address is required to confirm your account. Regardless of whether you register a username or not, your IP address is recorded when you comment as part of our effort to combat spam and inappropriate comments.

The blog has an "email this post to your friend" feature that lets you send a particular post in email format to up to 5 email addresses. To use this feature, we require that you provide your name and email addresses, as well as the names and email addresses of the persons you are sending the post. These information is recorded electronically and purged periodically. We do not keep these personal information and do not use it for any purpose other than to compile an aggregate statistical information (i.e. how many posts were emailed – not to or by whom).

In order to process and ship your order, we require your personal information such as name, address, and telephone number, as well as financial information such as credit card number and expiration date. You may register a username in the online shop (for security purpose, this is separate from the blog/forum/Upcoming Queue username). This allows you to track the progress of your order. You may also place an order through a quick checkout procedure (without prior registration of a username). If we have trouble processing your order, we will use this information to contact you.

In addition to personal information, we may also collect aggregate information about our visitors (that does not personally identify you), such as operating system, the browser you are using, the country of you are located, referring domain, and the domain name of your internet service provider.

**Use of Personal Information**

_Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)_  
We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our partners and advertisers. This information does not identify individual users **.**

_Personally Identifiable Information  
_ We do not share, sell, or rent personally identifiable information with third parties. We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website.

_Agents_  
To fulfill your online order, we may use an outside shipping company to fulfill drop-shipped orders, as well as a credit card processing company to bill you for goods. These companies do not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information for any other purpose.

_Cookies_  
A cookie is a small text file stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. In some cases, we link the information stored in cookies to personally identifiable information you submit while on this site.

We use both short-term (session) and long-term (persistent) cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our website, for instance so you can comment on the blog and post on the forum without having to log in multiple times. Persistent cookies remain on your computer’s hard drive for an extended period of time. By storing your login information, you do not have to log into your account every time you visit this website. You can remove persistent cookies by following the directions provided in your Internet browser’s help file.

Some of our business partners (advertisers) use cookies on our website. We have no access or control over these cookies. This privacy policy covers the use of cookies by Neatorama.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. See "Third Party Advertisers" below.

**Third Party Advertisers**

Ads on Neatorama.com are served by third party advertisers. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visit to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here:

**Privacy Policy Changes**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time, solely in our discretion. We encourage visitors to frequently check this page for any changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact us via email.

**COMMENT**

|
